Vitalii Kovtounenko



vitalykovtunenko92@gmail.com

Vitalii-kovtounenko-6b0329177 vitko-swe.github.io/web-portfolio



Summary

Highly motivated Purdue University – West Lafayette computer science graduate. My experience includes back-end development, web development, and basic knowledge of Cloud Computing. Familiar with Scrum; an agile development methodology. Very dedicated, goal-oriented, and a great team player. Passionate about technology, innovation and entrepreneurship and looking forward to expanding my horizon, developing meaningful applications, and learning new skills in software engineering.

Education

Purdue University, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – West Lafayette, IN 05/2021 **Concentration: Software Engineering** GPA: 3.31/4.0

Entrepreneurship and Innovation certificate

Prairie State College, Associate of Science - Chicago Heights, IL

05/2018

GPA: 3.94/4.0

Skills

Technical: Java, C/C++, Python

Familiar with: AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Unix/Linux, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, MySQL, Scrum, Microservices

Languages: Fluency in English, Hebrew, and Russian

Projects

HopScotch (group): 01/2021 - 05/2021

- Created a web application that centralized all aspects of trip planning including flights, hotels, attractions and dining
- Compiled many third-party services into one search
- Implemented RESTful API using node.js and used MySQL database to take advantage of intertwined relations in data
- Worked with React on the client side which allowed easy customization of UI

Cloud services (Individual) 04/2021 - 05/2021

- Constructed storage, compression and web microservices using docker and python
- Achieved communication between microservices by using RESTful gueries
- Managed containerized microservices using Kubernetes

Decision Tree Classifier (Individual):

09/2020 - 10/2020

- Employed an ID3 algorithm in Python to predict who will survive and die in the Titanic dataset
- Incorporated k-fold cross validation, minimum sample split size, maximum depth, and post pruning to reduce overfitting and generalize better for unseen data
- Achieved 86% prediction accuracy by defining the maximum depth of the decision tree

Web Server (Individual):

04/2020 - 05/2020

- Created a multithreaded HTTPS webserver with three concurrency modes: fork, thread, and pool of threads using C++
- Services GET requests, allows web-browsable directories and maintains server logs

Other Experience

Equipment Center/Entry Control - Purdue Recreational and Wellness Center

05/2019 - 05/2021

Primary contact for patrons entering the facility or renting equipment

Security Supervisor – Waldorf Astoria Hotel, Jerusalem

09/2014 - 07/2016

Provided security for hotel and guests, ensuring guests wellbeing and protecting against terror attacks and fires

Military - Israel Defense Forces (IDF), Sergeant

08/2011 - 08/2014

Served in the infantry as an Explosive Ordnance Disposal specialist